Rebekah Monson

rebekah@whereby.us

rebekahmonson.com

About

Rebekah Monson is a VP of Product and Editorial with more than a decade of experience in journalism, technology, online media and design. She is an active collaborator with a proven ability to manage complex problems, tight deadlines and challenging business conditions.

Experience

Co-founder and V.P., Product and Editorial

WhereBy.Us

October 2014 to present

WhereBy.Us is a media startup that creates media and technology products to help people connect and engage in their cities.

- Design, develop and manage local media brands and brand strategy using iterative processes and human-centered design techniques.
- Design, develop, test and manage websites, daily email newsletters, ticketing systems, member management, sales, and additional technology products and systems.
- Manage editorial and cross-platform product and content strategy for local brands.
- Manage technology and local brand staff.
- Write, edit, and design editorial content, including articles, interactive media, and data visualization projects.

Communication Manager

University of Miami School of Communication

October 2013 to September 2014

- Planned and executed a comprehensive communications strategy for the School of Comunication.
- Oversaw branding and development of promotional materials, web and print collateral, multimedia projects, strategic communications, campaign materials and email marketing.
- Coordinated external media relations and press inquiries.
- Managed audience development across social platforms.
- Planned and executed a comprehensive strategy for the School of Comunication website, launched in 2014, that improved admissions requests and grew users by more than 20% in the first month of launch.

Editor

University of Miami College of Arts and Sciences

November 2011 to October 2013

- Planned and executed a comprehensive communications strategy for the College of Arts and Sciences.
- Oversaw branding and development of promotional materials, web and print collateral, a semiannual magazine, multimedia projects, strategic communications, campaign materials and e-mail marketing.
- Coordinated external media relations issues and press inquiries.
- Supervised a communications specialist, hired and managed freelancers and oversaw budgets for college communications.
- Managed brand and audience development across platforms.
- Assisted in the planning and execution of a comprehensive redesign strategy for the College of Arts and Sciences website, launched in 2013.

Teaching Assistant

University of Miami School of Communication January 2013 to May 2013

• Taught basic design principles, Adobe InDesign, Photoshop and Illustrator skills to two sections of a lab for communication students.

Reporter

Sun Sentinel

December 2010 to November 2011

- Covered community affairs and municipal government in Boca Raton and unincorporated southern Palm Beach County.
- Wrote daily breaking news stories and blogs, developed enterprise content from within coverage.
- Shot, edited and produced videos and multimedia coverage.
- Trained and assisted reporters with video production and editing.
- Used social media to communicate with readers, find stories and sources and break news.

Community manager

Sun Sentinel

August 2009 to December 2010

- Managed web presence, social media networks, blogs and online planning for the business section and subsections.
- Trained staff on software, SEO and social media tools.
- Grew local traffic by more than 30% for business content.

Design director

Sun Sentinel

March 2007 to August 2009

- Managed and art-directed up to five designers to produce daily 6- to 20-page Sports and Business sections on deadline.
- Collaborated with editors, reporters, photographers and graphic artists to plan daily coverage, projects and special sections.
- Helped to establish and maintain visual and typographic style.
- Illustrated and art-directed photo shoots for projects.
- Trained designers on publication software as a CCI superuser.
- Conceptualized and executed print and website redesigns.

Projects/1A Designer

Sun Sentinel

July 2005 to March 2007

Designer

Spokesman-Review

October 2003 to July 2005

Education

University of Miami

Incomplete.

Master of Fine Arts, Interactive Media

Louisiana State University

1999 to 2003

Bachelor of Arts, Mass Communication

Concentration: Journalism

Minor: Visual communication

Other

Organizations and Leadership

Society for News Design, Board of Directors

Code for Miami, Board of Directors, co-founder

FIU Engagement Advisory Council, member

Hacks/Hackers Miami,co-founder

Friends of the Underline, founding member, Young Professionals

Organization

Society of Professional Journalists South Florida Pro Chapter, Board of Directors (2011-2012)

Professional honors

Radical Partners Social Enrepreneurship Bootcamp, 2016

Knight Cities Challenge winner (CUT Group), 2016

Google Fellow, Personal Democracy Forum 2014

White House LGBT Innovation Summit, 2014

Five Tech Women to Watch in Miami, TechCocktail, 2015

Miami's Most Interesting People, Miami New Times, 2015

Reader, Knight News Challenge, 2013-2014

Judge, Society for News Design's 34th annual Best of News Design competition

Judge, Best of Sports Design competition 2013-2014

Awesome Foundation grantee (Sensor Sub) 2014

Awards from the Society for News Design, Society for Professional Journalists, Florida Society of Newspaper Editors, SPJ's Sunshine State awards, Best of Gannett contests.

Speaking and workshops

Institute for Nonprofit News (INN) Technology Workshop, 2016

SNDSF Conference Committee, 2016

Hacks/Hackers Connect London, 2016

Hacks/Hackers Connect Miami, 2016

NICAR, Twine workshop, 2015

Code for America Summit, brigade panelist, 2014

Newsgeist, 2014

Online News Association, Newsgames session, 2014

Indiecade, big games showcase, 2014

AEJMC, ONA Challenge Grant panelist, 2014

Grace Hopper, Student Opportunity Lab session, 2014

WordCamp Miami, Wordpress for Journalists session, 2014

#SNDMakes Indianapolis, 2014

Miami Arts Business Council, 2014

NAHJ Build A Site Workshop, instructor, 2014

Kauffman-Rossin Millennials in the Workplace Panel, 2014

NewsFoo, 2013

Code for America Summit, 2013

SPJ Florida/NAHJ Multimedia Workshop, Mobile video for journalists session, 2013